## **RESUME**

#### **RUPALEE SHRIVASTAVA**

Mobile-7795651153

email: rupaleeshrivastava@gmail.com.

### **Career Objectives**

To be associated with an organization that provides me an opportunity to show my skills, improve my knowledge with the latest trends and to be a part of the team that works dynamically towards the growth of the organization. With a brilliant professional record I aspire to join as **Software Developer** where in my diligence and extensive experience contributes to the growth of the organization within the **IT/Finance sector**.

## **Experience Summary**

Decisive, Results-Focused professional offering an experience of over 2 years. Excellent analytical skills summed up with strong knowledge in coding and development in Core Java, JSF, JSP, SQL Server 2000/2005, and PL/SQL. Implementations and Testing Methodologies. Relevant exposure of working in Linux environments.

#### **Technical Skill Set**

Programming languages	Core Java,J2EE C.
<b>Database Management</b>	SQL Server 2008 and 2005,PL/SQL,MYSQL
Web Technology	Java Script(JSF/JSP), HTML,XHTML
Familiar with	C language, Robots Framework
Markup Language	HTML,XHTML
<b>Operating systems</b>	Windows XP, Windows 7, Linux

# **Work Experience**

# Project Engineer – Core Java Developer Wipro Technologies

Dec 2010 – Present

# **Project Experience**

1.	Project Title	ACS(Adaptation Common Services)	
	Duration	Sept 2011 – Present	
	Team Size/Location	14(Offshore)	
	Designation	Project Engineer	
	Project Details	Adaptation Common Services is network monitoring product. It manages networks, network elements. Adaptation Common Services also deals with Security Management. A packaged product comprising software and hardware, it is installed in networks and network elements.	
	Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Requirement Gathering for the new features to be incorporated within the product.</li> <li>Performance Analysis of the Entire System.</li> <li>Coding.</li> <li>Time and Effort estimation.</li> <li>Client Interactions and trainings regarding the product.</li> <li>Work allocation.</li> <li>Performing the Analysis for identifying and fixing the root cause which hampers the productivity of the team.</li> <li>Conduct training sessions for the team leads, team members on technology and product functionality.</li> </ul>	
	Environment	Core Java, JSF, Red Hat Enterprise Linux, ADS, EJB, Robots Framework	

2.	<b>Project Title</b>	EVC(Electronic Vehicle Charging)		
	Duration	May 2011 Till Aug 2011		
	Team Size	6		
	Designation	Project Engineer		
	j	Electronic Vehicle Charging monitors charging of vehicles by using electricity. A packaged product comprising software and hardware, it is installed in charging station at the petrol pumps. Customer can harge the vehicle by using charging port of the charging station and nake the payment.		
	Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Requirement Gathering for the new features to be incorporated within the product.</li> <li>Performance Analysis of the Entire System.</li> <li>Coding.</li> <li>Time and Effort estimation.</li> <li>Client Interactions and trainings regarding the product.</li> <li>Work allocation.</li> <li>Performing the Analysis for identifying and fixing the root cause which hampers the productivity of the team.</li> </ul>		
	Environment	Core Java, JSF, Junits, Power Shell, SQL 2008, Windows Server 2008		

## **Educational Qualification**

- B.Tech (Computer Science Engineering.) from Himachal Pradesh University with an aggregate of 71.89% during 2005 to 2009.
- Pursued 10+2 from North Point Public School, from I.C.S.E board with an aggregate of 61.30% in 2004.

• Pursued SSE (10<sup>th</sup>) from **D.A.V Public School**, from **C.B.S.E** board with an aggregate of 67.40% in 2002.

## **Training**

• Java Training from **HCL-CDC**(Noida).

## **Training Project**

## Project Details-1

<b>Project Name:</b>	SMART-INVESTOR.			
Role	Team Member.			
Organization	Alphanet Technologies Pvt. Ltd.			
Duration	07/07/2008—17/07/2008.			
Environment	Languages:	JAVA.		
(with skill	O/s :	Window XP.		
versions)	Database:	Mysql.		
Role	Understanding the project requirements.			
	Designing of Screens.			
	• Designi	<ul> <li>Designing of tables.</li> </ul>		

## Project -Description

Smart Investor is an expert system who provides tips to invest money in share market. It provides means to maintain portfolio of clients. Smart Investor is developed for Financial Services who are dealing in sale and purchase of shares on behalf of their clients. The core part of this application which makes it different from other related applications is that it provides proposed system which is used to help end user when to purchase and when to sell and how many shares are to be purchased and sold so that at all levels client will have the capacity to purchase the shares. In this application, MySql database is used to store data related to

employee, share, clients, etc. Since database is on Server, so any number of users can work simultaneously and can share their data with each other.

### Contributions

- Analysis of requirement provided.
- Designing of Screens.
- Designing of tables.
- Coding.

#### **Interests**

- Playing Badminton.
- Participating in different Cultural Activities.
- Listening to music.
- Playing Sports.

#### **Achievements**

- Received first prize for Long Jump.
- Received first prize for Short-put.
- Received first prize for Kho-Kho.
- Once University topper of Math.

#### **Personal Details**

Father' Name
S.P. Shrivastava.
Date Of Birth
19 Feb 1988.

• **Nationality** : Indian.

• Language Proficiency : English, Hindi.

• Martial Status : Single.

• **Mobile** : 7795651153/7411988691

I hereby certify that all the information furnished is correct to best of my knowledge.

Place: Bangalore. (Rupalee Shrivastava)

Date: